You're sending me away to Saga?
That's right. It's where Master Hebea was born.
If I'm not mistaken, I believe that his wife passed away a long time ago,
so it should be quite a peaceful arrangement.
Honestly, I'm relieved.
Up against him, even the most notable dignitaries won't make a fuss.
He has wisdom and experience on his side,
and, well, you would know more about these matters than I could explain.
Proprietor, Madam, you have my thanks. I appreciate all that you've done.
In my years, I've never seen a courtesan like you before, Yugiiri.
And I'm afraid we never will again.
To gain so much popularity, she could no longer get customers? Unheard of.
I'm sorry if I have caused you any trouble.
I wish you the best life.
But knowing you, I shouldn't have cause to worry.
Oh my goodness, what have you girls been doing?
Yugiiri, are you leaving us? Will we see you again? Is Saga really far away?
Please don't go. I wanted you to teach me more about singing and dancing.
There, there, girls. She's a legendary courtesan who's starting a new life for herself.
You should be happy for her.
Come now. Don't cry. Now. Let me see you smile.
I may be far away in Saga, but I promise that each of you will remain close to my heart.
Well, technically, Saga doesn't actually exist anymore.
Huh?
Don't Lady Yugiri always look so beautiful?
Of course she does.
She's a legendary courtesan.
What makes her so legendary?
You're too young to understand.
Several months had passed since the legendary courtesan reluctantly left her old life.
However, Master Hebeah, the high-ranking government official who arranged her freedom, passed away due to sudden illness.
In accordance with his wishes, she was granted a portion of his fortune.
Despite the security her inheritance lent her, she faced the unfortunate prospect of living out the rest of her life in a town where she knew no one, and no one knew her.
They don't call her a legend without good reason.
I bet that girl puts the folks over in Kamiyashi-shou to shame.
Why would she leave that lifestyle behind?
Fresh treats!
Come on by!
Shirako, Manju, and Dango!
Step right up and enjoy!
Listen up, everyone!
The time has come for us to take a stand!
We must bring back Saga right now!
Saga!
Huh?
What a creep.
Let's go.
Attention!
Please stop by to watch our show!
It's the Shingoro Traveling Show!
We're only in town for seven days!
Saga!
Here, please take one, sir!
Hey, what the hell are you doing?
I'm sorry!
Watch where you're going!
I see you're outspreading propaganda again!
This time, you're coming with me!
Stop struggling!
Think I'll hold on to this for now.
Kiiichi Momazaki, why are you always out here causing me so much damned trouble?
Give it a rest before I haul you off to jail once and for all!
I just want the people to remember how Saga used to be!
Stop that thief!
He's getting away!
Don't move a muscle until I get back!
I'm coming!
Huh?
Oh.
Thank you, Ito.
Yeah, sure.
You just never learn, do you?
During that time, the members of the Meiji government considered Saga to be a problematic prefecture.
And in the Bakumatsu period, it underwent westernization faster than other domains, making Saga a key location during the Reformation.
But, with uprisings by the former samurai class during Meiji 7 and the accompanying defeats, its glory was tarnished.
By Meiji 9, Saga had been divided up between two prefectures, Mizuma and Nagasaki.
This resulted in its total erasure from the map.
You need to stop getting into trouble.
One day you're going to get yourself in it bad, and I won't be there to help you.
I can't just stop.
I want Saga back.
The way it used to be.
You're never going to accomplish anything if you keep doing this by yourself.
The Imperial Court still has their issues with Saga.
On top of that, nobody wants a repeat of the Saga war.
But I'm not trying to start a war!
That's how it comes across.
Let's say the Saga does get its name back.
What happens after?
I hadn't thought of...
Alright, enough of that.
Set aside the restoration of Saga, okay?
Let's go check out the cherry blossoms.
You'll love it.
It'll make you forget all about that old Saga you're so fond of.
Promise!
Huh?
You know I'm not really interested in that kind of stuff.
Hey, where's the meat?
I ate it all.
I'm going to get you!
If you think you can take me on, you just try me!
Teacher, you know, you would be the talk of the town if you weren't always cooped up in here.
Plus, the cherry blossoms are in bloom, and I know where all the best viewing spots are.
You're free now.
You should explore the outside world.
Wow, look at the battle!
It's pretty!
Huh?
Hmm?
Hmm.
Oh, is this yours?
Here.
Thank you, it is.
I bought it moments before.
Coming through!
Get out of the way!
Look out!
Please allow me to help you.
Oh no, I'm…
Here, use this.
Thank you very much.
Hey, this is mine.
I'm sorry, I had no idea.
I apologize for treating it like tissue paper.
You'll feel better once you change it to some dry clothes.
Oh, what happened to you?
She's an angel.
Huh?
I think I know who she is.
If I'm right, she's the legendary courtesan who moved to Saga at the end of last year.
Legendary?
Come on.
You mean you haven't heard of her?
Pay more attention to town gossip.
She's a renowned courtesan named Yugiri.
Her performances were unlike anything anyone in Edo had ever seen.
Men and women alike revered her.
Yugiri was in high demand to the point that her prices skyrocketed to an obscene amount.
No one could afford her entertainment anymore.
Leaders of the Restoration fought over her.
And it's rumored that the Meiji court almost fell apart because of it.
And now she lives in Saga?
Don't fall in love.
I'm not in love!
You couldn't possibly handle a woman like that.
She's from a different world.
Maybe I could learn more about her world.
Hello again.
You didn't need to go through such trouble just for me.
I know it's not much, but I wanted to say thank you for, uh...
I am touched that you thought of me, though.
Thank you, but you should run along home now.
The people in town might get the wrong idea.
But I don't care what they think.
See, all this talk about you being from a different world,
the complicated details about your history don't matter to me.
In our saga, it'll be…
Pardon me. Does a man by the name of Kiichi Momazaki live here?
Uh…
It's Saga. I am Saga. No, Saga is me!
Oh my! Are you all right, my lord?
Grandpa, did you wander off?
This is a remedy for colds and other illnesses.
A very nourishing collection of herbs.
I asked an old acquaintance to send it to me.
That's so kind of you. Thank you.
I was feeling a little guilty.
You braved that blazing sun just to bring me a simple gift of gratitude.
It's nothing. Besides, I wanted to do it.
It was so thoughtful.
Since I arrived in Saga, you're the first one to come calling,
other than my dance students.
I must apologize for my grandpa earlier.
He's a little unwell.
He seemed like an interesting man to me.
He was already on the decline.
But I think when Saga lost its name, he got even worse.
He started ranting some nonsense about how he'd be able to raise the dead
if only he had his old powers back.
About eight years ago, a big battle took place right here in Saga,
and my father was killed.
After that, I had no place to go.
I spent my days cowering in the wilderness.
I don't know what would have happened if Gramps hadn't found me.
I owe him more than I could ever give him.
The only thing he cares about,
the only thing he wants in return,
is for me to save Saga.
At first, I was confused by what that meant.
But then, when Saga lost its name,
it felt like everything my father died trying to protect slipped away.
And Saga might vanish from people's hearts, too.
But I couldn't let that happen.
I think that fate is responsible for bringing my grandpa and I together,
so that I could find my purpose in life.
Yugiri, from this day forward,
this is where you'll be living.
Finally, I have a clear vision for the future.
I know in my heart what I want to do now.
I want to create a new Saga.
A place where it doesn't matter what your status is or who you were before.
A place where anyone can choose their own paths in life,
and they can stay true to themselves.
Mm.
I see.
That sounds like a beautiful place to live.
Take one!
Please take one, sir!
You there!
You want to get arrested?
Very funny!
You never give up, do you?
Um, Yugiri helped me out some.
Fixing the composition and stuff.
Oh, haha, there, there.
There, it's okay.
Don't cry.
I'm here with our dinner.
Do forgive me, sir.
I felt an eerie presence, and perhaps I'm a little unnerved.
I'm so sorry!
I know I'm running late.
Huh?
Yito, you came early.
I guess I couldn't wait to meet the legendary courtesan, Yugiri.
Look, this big one is for you.
So huge!
You actually caught that thing in the Fukushoe River?
Wow!
Tasty!
I see your exceptional skills extend to cooking, as well.
The man who arranged my freedom for me taught me all kinds of new talents.
They've helped me to live in the outside world since.
Hmm.
I bet he did.
Perhaps you should do the same.
Same what?
I mean, it's never a bad idea to learn new skills.
You could become a scholar or a doctor.
If you really want to help people, you should focus on realistic goals,
instead of wasting your time trying to bring back the glory days of Saga.
You happened upon this nice lady.
Maybe it was a sign.
You know?
Maybe it's time for you to start a family.
Huh?
Being the head of a household gives a man a feeling of responsibility.
Don't you want that?
the game?
Huh?
No way!
Are you stupid!?
Seriously, what are you saying?
Why on earth made you say something so crazy?
Oh my.
Are you alright?
Right? Lord Kiichi?
He's always been such a lightweight.
That's all right.
Have one with me.
No, I'm fine.
Tell me, Lord Ito,
just how long have you and Lord Kiichi known each other?
We only met two years ago.
I heard about some oddball who was passing out strange pamphlets in the streets.
I was amused at first.
People seemed to ignore him,
walking right past him as if he weren't there.
Yet he never gave up.
He was so determined.
There had to be better ways to get the word out, but
to be honest, he's a fool.
This country's changed, and it's going to keep changing fast.
Nothing good will ever come of clinging to history.
I don't think Kiichi has any interest in bringing back the past.
He wants to create a more progressive saga.
It might be nothing more than a fantasy right now,
but he wants it, and I think that I want it too, to live in that saga.
Sooner or later, reality will set in, and he's going to get his heart broken.
This country isn't ready for that saga.
Not yet.
Thank you for this.
It was enlightening.
Please take one!
For Saga!
Sir, could you tell us more about the information in this handout?
We're after the same things that you are.
The old saga.
Those videos are there for the fact that you have this to match!
So, are there sleeping things?
Can you follow me unless I come out so,
what can be shared in front of my ear?
A default to her.
Nothing.
I'm thankful for this.
Thank you.
It's me, Yugiri. There's something truly inspiring about men willing to risk everything for their beliefs.
Next time on Episode 9 of Zombieland Saga Revenge, The Saga Incident Part 2. This is goodbye.